# **Anthony Chau Frias**

Android Developer

Chiclayo, Peru (GMT-5) (+51) 978897878 anthonysy21@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/anthonychaufrias

**Passionate** Android developer about creating native apps with **5 years** of experience using **Kotlin** and Java. One of my most outstanding achievements was **to speed up to 70%** of the reports of an educational institution's web system "Finanzas del alumno". What I am looking for in a company is to continue growing professionally, learning new things, and putting them into practice.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **TicSolu, Android Developer** — September, 2020 - December, 2022

- Built an **Android app** to satisfy the services of Food Delivery, and Order and Pick up Food.
- Created Unit and Integration tests to verify and guarantee the functionalities and processes.
- Integrated this app with Firebase Authentication, Google Maps, Firebase Cloud Messaging, Firebase Realtime Database, and Google Cloud services.
- Built the back end written in PHP and integrated it with Firebase to manage Push notifications.
- Published the app to Google Play.

<u>Tech Stack</u>: **Java(Android)**, **Kotlin**, XML, MySQL, PHP7, **Google** Play Console, **Firebase**, **Google** Cloud, Google Search Console, **JUnit** 

### TicSolu, Android and Web Developer — November, 2019 - March, 2020

- Developed a web **app** for the sale and stock management of mobile devices.
- Developed the mobile version of this software, an **Android app** with the same features.
- Integrated both **applications** with the Firebase services.

Tech Stack: Java(Android), Javascript, AngularJS, Firebase Authentication, Firebase Realtime Database

### **La Canastita, Android Developer** — February, 2018 - August, 2018

• Participated in the development of an E-commerce application for **android mobile** devices, improving by 40% the requests to the back-end, adding a security layer and token validations.

Tech Stack: Java(Android), XML, PHP5, MySQL

#### **TicSolu, Software Developer** — April, 2017 - December, 2017

- Improved the management and lifetime of the piling machines by up to 20% by developing the "Rice Piling Scheduling" functionality, depending on the available schedule, customer priority, the quantity of rice bags and availability of the piling machine.
- Developed a **mobile app** to allow customers to visualize the piling status of their rice bags. This increased the customer's trust in the Company(mill).
- Implemented the back end, which was oriented to support the requests coming from the **mobile app**.

<u>Tech Stack</u>: Java(Android), XML, PHP5, JQuery, JavaScript, MySQL

# **PROJECTS**

## People, GitHub Repository — <a href="https://bit.ly/github-people-v2">https://bit.ly/github-people-v2</a> — 2022

• Built a repository on **GitHub** about Kotlin based on **MVVM** and **Clean Architecture** using Dependency Injection and Testing. This is a CRUD template so any developer could build their projects based on this example.

Tech Stack: Kotlin, Git, GitHub, MVVM, Clean Architecture, Dagger Hilt, Unit Test, Integration Test, JUnit

### FastMind, Indie Videogame — <a href="http://bit.ly/fastmindgame">http://bit.ly/fastmindgame</a> — 2014 - 2019

• Created my first videogame, a personal project of which I am very proud because I was able to reach the **final round** in the "Indie Prize PERÚ2019 LITE" contest and from which I learned a lot since I experienced all the stages for this project. I integrated this game with Google Play Games Services to manage the leaderboards and achievements.

<u>Tech Stack</u>: **Java(Android)**, XML, Fireworks, **Google** Play Games Services, **Google** Play Services, **Google** Play Console, Google Cloud

### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Advanced: Java, PHP, PLSQL, JavaScript; Intermediate: Kotlin, C#, TypeScript
Frameworks, and Tools: Advanced: JQuery, AngularJS, Android Studio, Postman; Intermediate: Angular, Laravel, VS Code.

Databases: Advanced: MySQL, SQL Server; Intermediate: PostgreSQL, Oracle Database; Basic: MongoDB, TDD, Jetpack Compose.

Languages: Advanced: English; Native: Spanish.

### **EDUCATION**

**'Pedro Ruiz Gallo' National University** – Lambayeque, Peru. *Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering, September 2013* 

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Introduction to videogame design – Miríadax. 2017.

Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems – Coursera. 2014.

Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps – Coursera. 2014.

Being more creative – Coursera. 2013.